<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Home</title><link>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 18:28:20 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Network TUI</title><link>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/2023/08/network-tui/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 18:28:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/2023/08/network-tui/</guid><description>At the end of my previous blog post I mentioned about wanting to work on Textual, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share here my first project using Textual. I feel like for us network engineers, working on a CLI makes our work more enjoyable so naturally, building a TUI(Terminal User Interface) to do some of the automation tasks was a no-brainer to me. I have called it Net-TUI, a TUI application to do few network automation tasks.</description></item><item><title>Network Dashboard</title><link>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/2023/04/network-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 18:28:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/2023/04/network-dashboard/</guid><description>In this blog post I will be going through how I went about building a Network Dashboard using couple of my favorite Python libraries, Nornir and Rich. I&amp;rsquo;m quite sure that if you have been exploring the network automation world, you would have come across Nornir already. And similarly there is a very good chance that you have also come across Rich, which is in my opinion one of the coolest libraries out there!</description></item><item><title>Robot Framework 3</title><link>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/2022/08/robot-framework-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 10:13:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/2022/08/robot-framework-3/</guid><description>In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll be going through a Test Scenario which involves multiple Test Cases with some interesting checks. I will be covering only the new things I&amp;rsquo;ve added for this Test Scenario when compared to my earlier posts, which can be found here. Test Suite begins by validating the network status on a particular device, this involves checking protocols such as OSPF, BGP, Interface Status etc. After ensuring network is in steady state, a configuration change is executed and after the change, network is validated again to ensure there has been no network impact.</description></item><item><title>Robot Framework 2</title><link>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/2022/06/robot-framework-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 19:02:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/2022/06/robot-framework-2/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my first blog post as I mentioned there, I&amp;rsquo;m at a new job (well it&amp;rsquo;s been 2 months, so &amp;rsquo;newish&amp;rsquo;) and I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy getting to know the job(as with any job, there is a LOT to learn!).
Learning Robot Framework (RF) has been one of my objectives in these first few months as that is entirely new for me. As I continue to learn and explore RF, I wanted to take some time out to share few things I have learnt.</description></item><item><title>Robot Framework 1</title><link>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/2022/04/robot-framework-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 18:28:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sohanrai09.github.io/new-blog/2022/04/robot-framework-1/</guid><description>In my new job role as a Test Engineer, knowing how to use Robot Framework for Automating Test Cases is crucial, to save time and to make testing more fun! As I&amp;rsquo;m going through this learning journey, I wanted to blog about it for anyone who is looking to start this journey and also to help me understand things in a better way.
There are plenty of good resources out there which explains the Robot Framework and it&amp;rsquo;s components.</description></item></channel></rss>